Guide to the Nataliia Apollinarievna Logunova Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Nataliia Apollinarievna Logunova Papers,
1913-1972.
Logunova, Nataliia Apollinarievna, d. 1972?.
8 linear ft. (15 document boxes, 1 oversized folder).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library Bakhmeteff Archive New York, NY. 10027
BA#0236
4077771
The papers comprise correspondence, manuscripts, memoirs, diaries, personal documents, photographs, printed materials, periodicals, and clippings relating to the life and professional activities of Nataliia Logunova, a Russian émigré journalist and writer.
Biographical Note
1903, February 26: Nataliia Logunova (nee Ivanova) was born in Odessa, Russia.
1920: Her husband, Georgii Petrovich Logunov, died of typhus in Odessa. Later same year she left Russia and fled to Romania.
1944: Was deported to German camps.
1945-1952: Lived in various displaced persons and transition camps.
1952: Arrived to the United States of America.
1950s-1960s: Published articles in Russian emigre newspapers and magazines.
1962: Published a novel Irina.
1968: Published a novel Olen'ka Bell.
[1972]: Nataliia Logunova died.
Material is in Russian, English, and German.
Scope and Content
These papers contain the correspondence and writings of Nataliia Apollinarievna Logunova, a journalist and writer, who immigrated to the United States, and also published under the pseudonyms Nikolai Tallin, Nataliia Snarskaia, and NETLI.
The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, memoirs, diaries, documents, and printed materials. Among her correspondents are many prominent names, such as Georgii Adamovich, Rodion Berezov, Nikolai Losskii, Andrei Sedykh, Pitirim Sorokin, Iurii Terapiano, Alexandra Tolstaia, Mark Veinbaum, and others. Correspondence consists of incoming and outgoing letters from and to various people and organizations, including the emigre newspapers and journals Niva, Novoe Russkoe Slovo, Russkaia Mysl', Russkaia Zhizn', Sovremennik, and Vozrozhdenie. Manuscripts consist of unpublished short stories, poems, plays, novels, as well as published articles by Logunova. These also include typescripts of her two published novels, Irina and Olen'ka Bell. Unpublished memoir consists of a 12-part typescript under the title "Tri epokhi." Diaries cover the years 1945-1970 and personal documents cover a period of time when Nataliia Logunova lived in DP camps. Printed materials include copy of Logunova's published novel, Irina; short stories; journals and clippings, mostly authored by Logunova.
There are cross-references provided throughout the finding aid. When the cross-reference refers to another item within the same series, the reference includes the specific name or title and box and folder number (this also applies to the references within same subseries). If the cross-reference is to an item in another series, the reference includes the series number, series name, folder title, and box and folder numbers (this also applies to the references to items in another subseries).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in eight series.
Series I: Materials of Prominent Figures, 1949-197
Subseries I.1: Correspondence, 1949-1971
Subseries I.2: Manuscripts and Autographs, 1958-1959
Series II: Correspondence, 1950-1972
Subseries II.1: General Correspondence, 1950-1972
Subseries II.2: Subject Correspondence, 1962-1971
Subseries II.3: Outgoing Correspondence, 1965-1971
Series III: Manuscripts, 1913-1971
Subseries III.1: Prose; Poetry; Articles; Plays; Movie Scripts, 1913-1965
Subseries III.2: Memoirs, 1971
Series IV: Diaries, 1945-1970
Series V: Personal Documents, 1945-1952
Series VI: Photographs, 1957
Series VII: Printed Materials, 1943-1972
Subseries VII.1: Published Logunova's Writings, 1943-1972
Subseries VII.2: Research Materials, 1950s-1970s
Series VIII: Oversize Materials
Subjects
Adamovich, Georgii.; Akul'shin, Rodion, 1896-1988.; Argus, 1900-1970.; Berezov, Rodion Mikhaĭlovich, 1896- .; Dallin, Alexander, 1924-2000.; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959.; Dymow, Ossip, 1878-1959.; Gessen, Vladimir, 1901-; Grebenshchikov, Georgii, 1882-1964.; Grebenshchikov, Georgii, 1882-1964.; Kennedy, M. (Edward Moore), 1932-2009.; Khomitskii, Vsevolod.; Losskii, N. O. (Nikolaĭ Onufrievich), 1870-1965.; Narokov, Nikolai.; Poliakov, Aleksandr Abramovich, 1879-1970?; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979.; Sedykh, Andrei, 1902-; Sorokin, Pitirim Aleksandrovich, 1889-1968.; Terapiano, Iurii, 1894-1980.; Tolstoy, Alexandra, 1884-197.; Veinbaum, M. E. (Mark Efimovich), 1890-1973; Journalism.; Emigration and immigration--Soviet Union--20th century.; Emigration and immigration--Europe--20th century.; Refugees-- 1940-1950.; Refugee Camps--Germany.; Russian émigré́ literature in the twentieth century.; Russian literature.; Russian literature in foreign countries.; Russians--United States.; Articles.; Books.; Clippings.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Journals.; Letters.; Manuscripts (literary).; Memoirs.; Newspapers.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located on-site.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1965 Papers Nataliia A. Logunova Gift
- Series I: Materials of Prominent Figures, 1949-1971
  The series consists of correspondence, manuscripts, and autographs of prominent people. Organized into two subseries.
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence, 1949-1971
    Contains Nataliia Logunova's professional and personal correspondence with prominent people. Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
    - Adamovich, Georgii Viktorovich, 1968, (2 autograph letters signed) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Akul'shin, Rodion: see Berezov
    - Argus (aka Mikhail Konstantinovich Zheleznov and Mikhail Konstantinovich Aizenshtadt), undated, 1961, (2 autograph letters signed) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Berezov, Rodion Mikhailovich, 1950-1970, (3 autograph letters signed, 50 typed letters signed) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dallin, Alexander, 1955-1956, (4 autograph letters signed) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dulles, John Foster, undated, (2 autograph letters signed) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dymow, Ossip (aka Perelman), 1958, (1 autograph letter signed) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Gessen, Vladimir Iosifovich, 1972, (1 typed letter signed) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Grebenshchikov, Georgii Dmitrievich, 1949-1956, (2 autograph letters signed, 6 autograph postcards signed, 1 autograph note signed) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Kennedy, Edward Moore, 1971, (1 typed letter signed) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Khomitskii, Vsevolod, 1964, (1 typed letter signed) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Losskiĭ, N. O. (Nikolaĭ Onufrievich), 1961, (1 autograph letter signed) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Narokov, Nikolai Vladimirovich, 1956-1967, (75 letters and cards) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Perelman, Osip: see Dymow
    - Poliakov, Aleksandr Abramovich, undated (2 autograph letter signed): see Series II: Correspondence--Subseries II.1: General Correspondence--Novoe Russkoe Slovo (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1961, (1 typed letter signed) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1959-1960, (3 typed letters signed) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Sedykh, Andrei, 1962-1968 (5 typed letters signed): see Series II: Correspondence--Subseries II.1: General Correspondence--Novoe Russkoe Slovo(Box 3, Folder 7) and Subseries II.2: Subject Correspondence--Olen'ka Bell (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Sorokin, Pitirim, 1964, (1 autograph letter signed) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Terapiano, Iurii Konstantinovich, 1961-1970, (9 autograph letters signed) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Tolstaia, Aleksandra L'vovna, 1969, (1 autograph letter signed, 2 autograph notes signed) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Veinbaum, Mark Efimovich, 1949-1968 (31 typed letters signed, 1 typed letter, 1 autograph letter signed): see Series II: Correspondence--Subseries II.1: General Correspondence--Novoe Russkoe Slovo(Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Subseries I.2: Manuscripts and Autographs, 1958-1959
    Holograph inscriptions in an album "Kniga znakomstv, mimoletnykh i prodolzhitel'nykh, serdechnykh i poverkhnostnykh, lichnykh i pis'mennykh". Album also contains inscriptions by other people, who are not listed in the finding aid.
    - Argus (aka Mikhail Konstantinovich Zheleznov and Mikhail Konstantinovich Aizenshtadt), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Berezov, Rodion Mikhailovich, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Gessen, Vladimir Iosifovich, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Narokov, Nikolai, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Sedykh, Andrei, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Veinbaum, Mark Efimovich, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1950-1972
  The series consists of Nataliia Logunova's professional and personal correspondence with various people and organizations. Organized into three subseries. Correspondence on various subjects forms part of other series and subseries of the collection and remains in the files where it logically belongs.
  - Subseries II.1: General Correspondence, 1950-1972
    Incoming and outgoing correspondence with individuals and organizations. Organized in alphabetical order by correspondent's name. Unidentified correspondence is stored at the end of the subseries.
    - Academy Film Production, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Andreevskii, Boris Georgievich, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Belosel'skii, Sergei Sergeevich, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Belousov, Konstantin: see Russian Emigrants' Publishing Fund
    - Blonskii, N., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bogoliubov, Konstantin: see Tarydina, Tat'iana
    - Boland, Edward P., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bol'shukhin, Iurii, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bransburg, Marius, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Buguraev, M., 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Chaplinskii, Vladimir Mikhailovich, 1962-1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      (see also: Subseries II.2: Subject Correspondence--Irina(Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Dordopolo, Vladimir, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Ershov, Petr Evgen'evich, 1950-1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Foster, Liudmila, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Gerlakh, Vladimir Leonidovich, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Gladyshevskii, Anatolii A.: see Nenadkevich, Fedor--Pertained correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Gorb, Fedor, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Grebenshchikova, Tatiana: see Series I: Materials of Prominent Figures--Subseries I.1: Correspondence--Grebenshchikov (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Grigorovich, V.: see Nenadkevich, Fedor--Pertained correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Ignat'ev, Aleksandr Vasil'evich, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Iutanova, Valentina A., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Katenev, N., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Khmara, Nina, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Khoroshenko, Prokopii, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Koriakov, M., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Krotenko, Nadezhda, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Krotkov, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Kruglovich, Evgenii, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Krylova, Valentina Nikolaevna, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      (see also: Subseries II.2: Subject Correspondence--Irina (Box 5, Folders 16, 18)
    - Library of Congress, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Lorvi, Ekaterina: see Nenadkevich, Fedor--Pertained correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Magidov, Robert Zakharovich, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Mead, Daniel S., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Mort, Viktor, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      (see also: Subseries II.2: Subject Correspondence--Irina (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Nashi Vesti: see Vertepov, Dimitrii
    - Nenadkevich, Adam Adamovich, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Nenadkevich, Fedor Adamovich:
      - Letters to Logunova, 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 2 to 5)
      - Logunova's letters to him, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Logunova's letters to him, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Pertained correspondence, 1958-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Nikolenko, Lada, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Niva 1955-1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Nixon Office, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Novikova, Nadezhda, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Novoe Russkoe Slovo 1955-1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Orlich, Valentina, 1966-1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Pavlova, Iu., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Perov, Pavel Nikolaevich, 1961-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      (see also: Subject Correspondence--Irina (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Pliushkova, A., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Polchaninov, Mikhail, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Polchaninov, Rostislav, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Popov, Igor', 1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Publishers, 1960-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11 to 13)
    - Rais, Anatolii, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Readers, 1953-1968 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Russian Ecclesiastical Mission in Jerusalem, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Russian Emigrants' Publishing Fund, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Russian Immigrants' Representative Association in America, Inc., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Russkaia Mysl', 1958-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Russkaia zarubezhnaia kniga, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Russkaia Zhizn' 1953-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Sakevich, Igor': see Nenadkevich, Fedor--Pertained correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Samarin, Vladimir Dmitrievich, 1956-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      (see also: Subject Correspondence--Irina (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Shcherbakov, S., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Slavinskii, Mikhail Viktorovich, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Soglasie 1953 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Soiuz bor'by za osvobozhdenie narodov Rossii / SBONR, 1963-1970 (Box 4, Folder 12 to 14)
      (oversize newspaper clippings and one poster were removed and stored along with other oversize materials in a Flat Box)
    - Solov'ev, Mikhail, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Sorkin, Vladimir, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Sovremennik, 1963-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Stanfield, Boris, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Stoun, Naum Il'ich (aka Stone), 1954-1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Tanchyk, Elizaveta, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Tarsaidze, Alexandre, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Tarydina, Tat'iana, 1964-1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Trushchev, Konstantin Mikhailovich, 1959-1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      (see also: Subject Correspondence--Irina (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Tsentral'noe ob'edinenie politicheskikh emigrantov iz SSSR (Ts.O.P.R.), 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Tserkovno-prikhodskoi komitet Sv.Nikolaevskoi russkoi pravoslavnoi tserkvi v Springfield, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Tsvetikov, Alexis N., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Ugriumov, Aleksei Ivanovich, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Ustupnyi, Nikolai Dmitrievich, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Vainberg, Vladimir Samoilovich, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Vardanian, Grigorii Arsen'evich, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Vertepov, Dimitrii Petrovich, 1957-1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Vikis, Klavdiia A., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Voloshin, Aleksandr Aleksandrovich, 1951-1961 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Vozrozhdenie, 1958-1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Zavalishin, Sergei Vladimirovich, 1957-1961 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Zemtsova, N., 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Zergidi, A., 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Zhukov, V., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Zinchenko, Vitalii Petrovich i Valentina Vasil'evna, 1962-1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      (see also: Subject Correspondence--Irina(Box 5, Folders 16, 18)
    - Zolotarev, Vasilii Nikolaevich, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      (see also: Subseries II.2: Subject Correspondence--Irina (box 5, folders 16, 18)
    - Unidentified, 1951-1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Subseries II.2: Subject Correspondence, 1962-1971
    Correspondence on various subjects. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Irina, 1962-1966 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      (readers' reviews)
    - Irina and Olen'ka Bell, 1962-1969 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      (reviews)
    - Olen'ka Bell, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Operation Keelhaul (Resolution 399) and Soviet Sailors, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      (oversize newspaper clippings were removed and stored along with other oversize materials in a Flat Box)
    - Pasternak, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Subseries II.3: Outgoing Correspondence, 1965-1971
    Organized in chronological order.
    - 1965-1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Series III: Manuscripts, 1913-1971
  The series comprises Nataliia Logunova's writings: prose, poetry, articles, plays, movie scripts, and memoir. Organized into two subseries.
  - Subseries III.1: Prose; Poetry; Articles; Plays; Movie scripts, 1913-1965
    Holograph manuscripts, typescripts, drafts, notebooks, and notes. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Untitled, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "Beloi akatsii…," 1963 (Box 6, Folder 2 to 3)
    - "Belye tsapli," 1944 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "Bespravnyi" (povest'), undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "Bez rodiny" ("Bezdomnye", "Iz zhizni Di Pi"), 1950 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "Chernye," 1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Detskie p'esy:
      - "Krasnaia shapochka," 1949 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - "Vania i Masha," 1954 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Programma detskoi elki v Springfilde, Massachusetts, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "Dve zhenshchiny," undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - "Gvozdi v kresle," 1944 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Irina 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 11 to 14)
    - "Kogda skuchaet Amur," 1944 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Kommunizm bez prikras," undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Man without a face" ("Nelegal"), undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Olen'ka Bell, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 4 to 7)
    - "Pered litsom vechnosti," 1952 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Pionerka Olia," 1944 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Poetry, 1913-1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "Predverie Ameriki," 1952 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Proidennyi etap (Dnevnik byvshego DiPi)," undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "Samyi luchshii," 1949 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "Smert' Ivana Ivanycha," 1963 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Snezhnaia koroleva," [1940s] (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Snezhnaia respublika," 1964 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "Sovetskii Soiuz-Germaniia-Amerika" (articles), 1949-1965 (Box 8, Folder 5 to 6)
    - "Tri korotkikh rasskaza," undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "Zhizn' nachinaetsia snachala", 1955-1960 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Notebook (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Various notes (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Manuscripts by others: Autograph album "Kniga znakomstv, mimoletnykh i prodolzhitel'nykh, serdechnykh i poverkhnostnykh, lichnykh i pis'mennykh" (prose and poetry inscriptions by various people), 1957-1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Subseries III.2: Memoirs, 1971
    Typescript.
    - "Tri epokhi" (parts 1-2) (Box 8, Folder 11 to 14)
    - "Tri epokhi" (parts 2-3) (Box 9, Folder 1 to 8)
- Series IV: Diaries, 1945-1970
  Notebooks with holograph entries and newspaper clippings inserts.
  - 1945-1957 (Box 10, Folder 1 to 12)
  - 1957-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1 to 8)
- Series V: Personal Documents, 1945-1952
  Contains Logunova's personal documents related to DP period, such as IDs, passes, certificates, applications, photo IDs, and other. Arranged chronologically.
  - Personal documents related to DP period (Box 11, Folder 9 to 10)
- Series VI: Photographs, 1957
  The series includes 1 color print depicting Nataliia Logunova. More photographs 1940s-1950s attached to her IDs and stored along with personal documents in Series V: Personal Documents (box 11, folders 9-10). One color photo attached to the autograph album, which is a part of the Series I: Materials of Prominent Figures--Subseries I.2: Manuscripts and Autographs (box 1, folder 18).
  - Logunova, Nataliia, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Series VII: Printed Materials, 1943-1972
  Books, periodicals, and clippings with Nataliia Logunova's writings and research materials.
  - Subseries VII.1: Published Logunova's Writings, 1943-1972
    Copy of Irina; mimeographed edition of short stories; journals and clippings (organized in scrapbooks) with articles. Periodicals arranged in alphabetical order by title.
    - Irina. Buenos-Aires: Seiatel', 1962 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      (novel in two parts)
    - Sbornik rasskazov (na pravakh rukopisi). Germany, (mimeographed edition) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Articles in Periodicals:
      - Detskii Listok, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Fellows of Odessa: Souvenir Journal 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Khristianskii vestnik 1943 (Box 12, Box 3)
      - Nashi vesti 1957-1959 1966, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Niva 1955 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Poslednie izvestiia 1947 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Rodnye dali 1955 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Seiatel', 1963 1968 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Soglasie, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Sovremennik (Toronto), 1965-1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Svoboda, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Vestnik russkoi monarkhicheskoi mysli, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Vozrozhdenie: La Renaissance, Literaturno-politicheskiia tetradi, 1960, 1962, 1965, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Scrapbooks with clippings:
        - #1: 19491-952 (Box 13, Folder 4)
        - #2: 1952-1957 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - #2-7: 1957-1963 (Box 14, Folder 1 to 6)
        - #8-12: 1963-1972 (Box 15, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Subseries VII.2: Research materials, 1950s-1970s
    Clippings and publications.
    - Newspapers Clippings, 1950s-1970s (Box 15, Folder 6)
      (oversize clippings were removed and stored along with other oversize materials in a Flat Box)
    - Congressional Records: Senate, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Muir News-Bulletin, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Series VIII: Oversize Materials, 1950s-1970s
  Includes oversize newspaper clippings, flyer, and poster. Materials stored in one oversized folder in Flat box
  - Newspaper clippings with Logunova's articles (Box Flat Box)
  - Newspaper clippings with research articles (Box Flat Box)
  - Poster and flyer (Box Flat Box)